So how do we arrive at a recommendation?
At this point in the process, we've gone through
the first three steps of the hypothesis-led approach.
We've defined the problem, we've structured the problem,
and we've prioritised the issues.
And now it's time for the last four steps.
So now we're going to think about how we plan
the analysis, and how we conduct the analysis —
how we arrive at a synthesis of what we've done,
and ultimately drive to a recommendation.
Let's spend a moment on each of those.
So let's talk about planning the analysis. When you think
about the work to be done, start with the prioritised issues.
What is your hypothesis against each of those?
What are you trying to prove or disprove?
What analysis do you need to conduct in order to do that?
And then, ultimately, think about accountability:
who is going to do that analysis, and by when?
And one of the challenges we see here —
is thinking about the interdependencies, solving for the timing,
and making sure each analysis is discrete enough to be tackled properly.
Now, conducting the analysis: this will vary
depending on the type of analysis being done.
It could be qualitative. It could be quantitative.
But there are a couple of things you want
to think about to do it well.
It's not just “are we busy?” — it's “what are we busy about?”
How is this helping us drive to the answer
to the problem we're trying to solve?
And when we do the analysis, we want to think about
how we can be as efficient as possible.
Can we get to the 80/20 solution and save time,
or do we need to go all the way to the exact, precise answer?
And the last point on analysis is
to constantly ask yourself —
is this analysis helping us get to the “so what”?
Which leads us to the next step in the problem-solving
process, which is all about synthesis.
I often ask myself: what is the difference between
a synthesis and a summary — and which one is better?
Well, a summary is simply a chronological recount
of everything that you've done.
A synthesis, on the other hand, is an integrated
“so what” of everything you've done in the work.
When you have the synthesis,
you're almost done — but not quite,
because the synthesis is simply
the outcome of the “so what”.
A recommendation is what you actually need to do
to achieve the value creation, or the impact, of the work.
Put differently: think about your recommendation as the way
you mobilise and pragmatically implement your strategy.
There are many ways to think about this.
For example, we often use the influence model to think about
all the pieces your strategy — or your recommendation —
needs to dock into, so that you're able to realise the impact.
Be mindful here.
Getting the organisation to align and mobilise
is half of the battle.
You may have the most elegant solution, but without buy-in,
without the conviction of the organisation,
you may not achieve the full impact
you initially intended.
So one of the challenges related to that is:
have you thought about —
de-biasing some of the challenges — the confirmation bias, for one.
If you get to a “so what” in the first week of a project,
how do you make sure you're still open-minded,
challenging it to get to the right solution overall —
not just the right answer from week one?